Register to The Armin Loos Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Musical works by Loos, 1918-1971; Series XIV
  - Index by medium, XIV.D
    - Orchestra, XIV.D.1
      - Preghiera -- A, 1933 Jun 5; 1 (Box 6, Folder 106)
      - Prelude for full orchestra. See: Lento. -- B, no date; 3 (Box 10, Folder 144)
      - Prelude to Easter. See: Lento., no date; 3 (Box 10, Folder 144)
      - Preludio e fuga à 9 voci? -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 146)
      - Preludio II (in memoriam Edgar Allan Poe) -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 146)
      - Procession -- A, 1939; 1 (Box 6, Folder 111)
      - Psalm 120, for chorus and orchestra -- A, 1963 Oct 15; 2 (Box 9, Folder 130)
      - [Songs, chamber orchestra acc., op. 2] -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 151)
      - The specter dances -- B, no date; 2 (Box 11, Folder 151)
      - [Stabat mater] -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 151)
      - [Suite, string orchestra, no. 1] -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 151)
      - [Symphony, no. 2] -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 151)
      - [Symphony, no. 2, D minor] -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 151)
      - [Symphony, no. 2] (to the United Nations) -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 151)
      - [Symphony, no. 3] -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 151)
      - [Symphony, no. 3] (different?). -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 152)
      - [Symphony] -- A, 1941; 1 (Box 7, Folder 123, Box 4)
      - [Symphony, string orchestra] -- A, 1940-1944; 5 (Box 6, Folder 114-116, Box 7, Folder 117-119)
      - [Symphony, string orchestra, no. 4] -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 152)
      - Toccata, intermezzo, finale? -- A, [1933-1934?]; 1 (Box 6, Folder 107)
      - Visione -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 152)
      - [Works, orchestra] -- A, 1967; 1 (Box 9, Folder 135)
      - [Works, orchestra. Sketches] -- A, 1922; 1 (Box 5, Folder 97)
    - Piano, XIV.D.2
      - To Bah, Bah Blacksheep -- B, no date; 2 (Box 10, Folder 143)
      - Barcarolle d'Hercule Amoureux -- A, 1929-1953; 1 (Box 5, Folder 101)
      - Capriccio -- A, 1938; 1 (Box 6, Folder 110)
      - La Chasse -- B, no date; 1 (Box 10, Folder 143)
      - Drei Improvisationen über ein Quartetthema -- A, 1919; 1 (Box 5, Folder 97)
      - Elegia -- B, no date; 1 (Box 10, Folder 143)
      - Eos -- A, 1923-1924; 6 (Box 5, Folder 98)
      - Fantasia -- A, 1931-1952; 1 (Box 5, Folder 103)
      - For my wife -- B, no date; 1 (Box 10, Folder 143)
      - Feuille d'Album -- A, 1930 Jun 16; 1 (Box 5, Folder 102)
      - Gesang am Lagen des Prometheus -- A, 1924 jan 13; 1 (Box 5, Folder 98)
      - In admiration of the Red Army -- A, 1942; 1 (Box 7, Folder 123)
      - [ie. Klavier Auszug für 2 pianos, 8 Händel -- A, 1926; 1 (Box 5, Folder 101)
      - Kyrie and Et in spiritum sanctum -- B, no date; 1 (Box 10, Folder 143)
      - March -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 146)
      - Musica ? sopra un thema continuo (quasi passacaglia) -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 146)
      - Music for 2 pianos -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 146)
      - Musik: Die Weit über den verlorenen Groschen -- A, 1925 Apr 1; 5 (Box 5, Folder 100)
      - November nights -- A, 1929 Oct 12; 1 (Box 5, Folder 101)
      - [Overture, piano] -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 146)
      - Pezzo pastorale? -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 146)
      - [Pieces, piano] -- A, 1941 Apr 2; 1 (Box 7, Folder 120)
      - [Pieces, piano] -- A, 1967; 2 (Box 9, Folder 135)
      - [Pieces, piano] -- B, no date; 2 (Box 11, Folder 146)
      - [Pieces, piano. Sketches], 1933 Jun 9-14; 1 (Box 6, Folder 106)
      - Prayer for February 11, 1938 -- A, 1938 Feb 11; 1 (Box 6, Folder 109)
      - Prayer for my wife -- A, 1937 Jun 28; 1 (Box 6, Folder 109)
      - Prayer for my wife (different?) -- A, 1937 Jul 8; 1 (Box 6, Folder 109)
      - Prayer for my wife (different?) -- A, 1937 Jul 12; 1 (Box 6, Folder 109)
      - Prayer for my wife (different?) -- A, 1937 Jul 21; 1 (Box 6, Folder 109)
      - Preghiera I (different) -- A, 1933 Apr 30; 1 (Box 6, Folder 106)
      - Preghiera III -- A, 1933 Apr 26; 1 (Box 6, Folder 106)
      - Preghiera VII -- A, 1933 May 7; 1 (Box 6, Folder 106)
      - Preghiera -- A, 1933 May 4; 1 (Box 6, Folder 106)
      - Preghiera (different?) -- A, 1933 May-Jun; 1 (Box 6, Folder 106)
      - Preghiera (different?) -- A, 1933 May 24; 1 (Box 6, Folder 106)
      - Preghiera (different?) -- A, 1933 May 28; 1 (Box 6, Folder 106)
      - Preghiera (different?) -- A, 1933 Jun 4-5; 1 (Box 6, Folder 106)
      - Preghiera for my wife -- A (different?), 1933 Apr 23-24; 1 (Box 6, Folder 108)
      - Preghiera für Klavier I -- A, 1933 Apr-May; 3 (Box 6, Folder 106)
      - Preghiera für mein Weib -- A, 1934 Nov 15; 1 (Box 6, Folder 108)
      - Preghiera, um Stellung für mein Wirt -- A, 1922 Jul 14; 1 (Box 5, Folder 97)
      - [Preludes, piano] -- A, 1946; 3 (Box 5, Folder 96, Box 7, Folder 123)
      - Preludietto -- A, 1937 Jan; 1 (Box 6, Folder 109)
      - Psalm 120, for chorus (SATTB) and orchestra -- A, 1963 Oct 15; 6 (Box 9, Folder 131, Box 4)
      - So? -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 151)
      - [Sonata, piano, no. 1] -- A, 1963 Jun; 2 (Box 9, Folder 131)
      - [Sonata, piano, no. 2] -- A, 1966; 5 (Box 9, Folder 134)
      - [Sonata, [piano?], no. 2] -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 151)
      - [Sonata, piano, no. 3] -- A, 1967; 5 (Box 9, Folder 135)
      - Sonatina -- A, 1930; 1 (Box 5, Folder 102)
      - Sonatina -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 151)
      - Studie nach Mozart? -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 151)
      - [Suite, piano] -- A, 1937-1938; 1 (Box 6, Folder 109)
      - Toccata -- A, 1929 May 3; 2 (Box 5, Folder 99)
      - [Toccata, piano, no. 3] -- A, 1925 Feb 11; 2 (Box 5, Folder 100)
      - [Variations, piano, Op. 5] -- A, 1930; 1 (Box 5, Folder 102)
      - Vier Nachstimmungen -- A, 1919 Dec 14; 1 (Box 5, Folder 97)
      - War Suite -- A, 1941; 4 (Box 7, Folder 120, Box 4)
      - [Works, piano, no. 3] -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 152)
      - [Works, piano] -- A, 1930 Mar 11; 1 (Box 5, Folder 102)
      - [Works, piano] -- A, 1931; 1 (Box 5, Folder 103)
      - [Works, piano] -- A, 1933 May 21-23; 2 (Box 6, Folder 106)
      - [Works, piano] -- A, 1933; 1 (Box 6, Folder 106)
      - [Works, piano] -- A, 1937 Jul 9; 1 (Box 6, Folder 109)
      - [Works, piano] -- A, 1937 Oct 18; 1 (Box 6, Folder 109)
      - [Works, piano] -- A, 1937; 1 (Box 6, Folder 109)
      - [Works, piano] -- A, 1939 Jul 25; 1 (Box 6, Folder 111)
      - [Works, piano] -- A, 1941 Apr 4; 1 (Box 7, Folder 120)
      - [Works, piano] -- A, 1941 Apr 10-11; 1 (Box 7, Folder 120)
      - [Works, piano] -- A, 1954 Apr 30; 1 (Box 8, Folder 126)
      - [Works, piano] -- A, 1960 Jul 3; 1 (Box 8, Folder 127)
      - [Works, piano] -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 152)
      - [Works, piano. Selections] -- A, 1918-1919; 2 (Box 5, Folder 96)
      - [Works, piano. Selections] -- A, 1924-1930; no date; 1 (Box 5, Folder 99)
      - [Works, piano. Selections] -- A, 1930; 5 (Box 5, Folder 102)
      - [Works, piano. Selections] -- A, 1932; 4 (Box 5, Folder 104)
      - [Works, piano. Selections] -- A, 1932; 1 (Box 5, Folder 105)
      - [Works, piano. Selections] -- A, 1933 Apr-May; 5 (Box 6, Folder 106)
    - Piano transcriptions and arrangements, XIV.D.3
      - Aquarius 70 -- A, [1970]; 1 (Box 10, Folder 141)
      - Lento: Prelude to Easter; arr. for piano, 4 hands -- B, no date; 1 (Box 10, Folder 144, Box 4)
      - [Pieces, orchestra, op. 4; arr. for 2 pianos] -- A, 1933; 1 (Box 6, Folder 106, Box 4)
      - Processional for Iris -- A, 1965 Jul 28; 1 (Box 9, Folder 134)
      - Psalm 120. à 5 voci -- A, 1963; 1 (Box 9, Folder 130)
      - [Quartet, string, no. 4] -- A, 1962-1963; 2 (Box 8, Folder 129, Box 4)
      - [Symphony, string orchestra; arr. for piano, 4 hands] -- A, [1944?]; 1 (Box 7, Folder 119)
    - Chamber, XIV.D.4
      - [Divertimento, piccolo, flute and 2 clarinets] -- B, no date; 1 (Box 10, Folder 143)
      - For four violins -- A, 1942; 1 (Box 7, Folder 123)
      - [Pieces, horn and piano] -- A, 1959-1963; 5 (Box 8, Folder 127)
      - [Quartet, oboe, horn, bassoon & piano] -- A, 1964; 3 (Box 9, Folder 132)
      - [Quartet, strings, no. 1] -- A, 1933-[1934]; 1 (Box 6, Folder 107)
      - [Quartet, strings, no. 3] -- A, 1939; 3 (Box 6, Folder 111)
      - [Quartet, strings, no. 3] -- B, no date; 2 (Box 11, Folder 147)
      - [Quartet, strings, no. 4] -- A, 1962-1983; 14 (Box 8, Folder 128-129)
      - [Quartet, strings, no. 5] -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 147)
      - [Quartet, strings] -- A, 1931-1933; 4 (Box 5, Folder 103)
      - [Quartet, strings] -- A, [1952?]; 1 (Box 8, Folder 126)
      - [Quartet, strings] -- B, no date; 2 (Box 11, Folder 147)
      - [Quintet, piano] -- A, 1910-1920; 5 (Box 5, Folder 97)
      - [Quintet, 2 violins, 2 violas, violoncello, and soprano] -- B, no date; 4 (Box 11, Folder 147-150, Box 4)
      - [Quintet, woodwind] -- A, 1964; 3 (Box 9, Folder 133)
      - Trio - Idea in search of configuration -- A, 1930-1960; 4 (Box 5, Folder 102)
      - [Variations, String quartet] -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 152)
    - String, XIV.D.5
      - [Sonata, violin, no. 2] -- A, 1970-1971; 3 (Box 10, Folder 142)
      - [Sonata, violin] -- A, 1968; 6 (Box 9, Folder 136)
    - Vocal, XIV.D.6
      - Canon e antiphonia: Prayer II, for chorus (SATB) and keyboard instrument -- B, no date; 1 (Box 10, Folder 143)
      - Le Dormeur du Val -- A, 1953; 1 (Box 8, Folder 126)
      - Elegy, for chorus of 6 voices -- A, [1937?]; 4 (Box 6, Folder 109)
      - Gesang am Nachmittag -- B, no date; 1 (Box 10, Folder 143)
      - Jesaia: XLV, 8, for 4 voices -- A, 1936 Mar; 1 (Box 6, Folder 108)
      - Kyrie, chorus (SMzATB) unacc. -- B, no date; 1 (Box 10, Folder 143)
      - Missa in signo terroris à 6 voci -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 146)
      - Missa spiritorum, for orchestra and chorus -- A, [1948?]; 1 (Box 12, Folder 159)
      - My light thou art, for chorus of 5 voices -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 146)
      - Peregrina, -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 146)
      - Prayer for my wife, for tenor and organ? -- A, 1936 Mar 29; 1 (Box 6, Folder 108)
      - Prayer for my wife and her family's happiness, for voice and piano -- A, 1937 Jul 4; 1 (Box 6, Folder 109)
      - Psalm 120, for chorus (SATTB) and orchestra -- A, 1938; 6 (Box 8, Folder 130, Box 4)
      - Psalm 120, à 5 voci (canon quintuplex), unacc. -- A, 1938 Mar 29-30; 1 (Box 6, Folder 110)
      - Silence, for chorus of 6 voices -- A, 1937 Jul 30; 1 (Box 6, Folder 109)
      - [Songs] -- A, 1930; 2 (Box 5, Folder 102)
      - [Songs] -- A, 1962 Mar; 6 (Box 8, Folder 127)
      - [Songs] -- A, 1962 Apr 1; 1 (Box 8, Folder 127)
      - [Songs] -- B, no date; 4 (Box 11, Folder 151)
      - [Songs, chamber orchestra acc., op. 2] -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 151)
      - [Stabat mater] -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 151)
      - Te deum, for 2 choruses (SATB) unacc. -- A, 1934; 1 (Box 6, Folder 108)
      - Trois sonnets de Rimbaud -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 152)
    - Study pieces, XIV.D.7
      - Study for 2 'cellos -- A, 1967; 2 (Box 10, Folder 138)
      - Study piece, for violoncello and piano -- A, 1969; 3 (Box 10, Folder 139)
      - Study pieces (II-III), for violoncello and piano -- A, 1969; 3 (Box 10, Folder 139)
      - Study piece for horn, 'cello, and piano -- A, 1969; 1 (Box 10, Folder 139)
    - Unspecified medium, XIV.D.8
      - Piece, unspecified medium -- A, 1969 May 29; 1 (Box 10, Folder 137)
      - Prayer for the return of my ticket and that the rug should be in the house -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 146)
      - Prelude (mind submerged in night feeling) -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 146)
      - [Sonata, unspecified medium, no. 2] -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 151)
      - [Sonata, unspecified medium] -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 151)
- Musical works copied or arranged by Loos, Series XV
  - Phantasy and fugue; arr. for orchestra., Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750; 1 (Box 12, Folder 158)
    Sketch signed, in ink and pencil. Score 35 cm.
  - [Die Gezeichneten. Overture] Vorspiel zür Oper: Die Gezeichneten., Schreker, Franz, 1878-1934; 1 (Box 12, Folder 158)
    Manuscript [in Loos's hand?], in ink. Condensed score ([10] p.); 34 cm.
- Sound Recordings, 1938-1979; Series XVI
  Sound recordings have been transferred to the Historical Sound Recordings Collection in the Music Library. For further information about archival recordings relating to Armin Loos, please contact the Curator of Historical Sound Recordings.